

# Nassim El Khantour

Multimedia Designer :: Art Director :: Web Developer

I am a French creative with an expertise in Web and Motion Design, but also proficiencies in development, 3D design, and illustration. An extended skill set I put at work in various projects for the past 5 years such as music videos, web apps, as well as audiovisual interactive setups.

- Montréal, Canada
- (+33) 6 35 17 69 16
- nasselkh
- nassim.elkhantour@gmail.com
- elkhantour.com
- in linkedin.com/in/nassimelkhantour
- Bē behance.net/elkhantour

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**



# Lead Motion Designer, Web & **Print Designer**

2022 - Present

Design of visual and interactive content going from websites to motion design assets.

- Production of motion design materials and sound design (google, meta, tiktoks ads, marketing collaterals, as well as product showcases...)
- Supervision of junior designers ensuring their work fit the established art directions.
- Design of websites and print assets.
- Branding and visual identity design.
- · Videography and photo editing of the agency's events and venues.
- Providing web developers JS libraries to improve websites user experience (3D WebGL interactive content, SVG/SCSS/GSAP animations...)
- Setup and development of web apps and Adobe extensions to enhance the agency workflow.

Redbox Media Inc. :: Montréal, Canada



# Web Designer & Developer

2020 - 2022

- Development and UX/UI design of LAOS: a web browser extension to improve Mandarin learning.
- Development and Web Design of an e-commerce coupled with a SQL client for products management.
- Development and UX/UI design of KINOJI: a website archiving various cinematographic content (MERN stack).
- Art direction, background painting and animation for an animated short-movie (music video).

Freelance:: Strasbourg, France



# Graphic & Multimedia designer

2016 - 2020

Providing visuals for various cultural structures such as associations, music acts and soundsystems.

- Spatial organisation and scenography of various video-mapping installations.
- Art direction and animation for an animated short-movie (music video).
- 3D modelling, animation and compositing of more than a 100 visual samples made to be projected during events.
- Development and UI design of interactive audiovisual software (motion design, generative art).

Independent contractor :: Nancy, France

# **EDUCATION**

#### DNSEP with summa cum laude

2019 - 2020

Master's degree in Digital Art.

ENSAD (École Nationale Supérieure d'Art et de Design) Nancy, France



# Web/Game Design, Illustration & **3D Animation**

2018 - 2019

International exchange program.

IUP (Indiana University of Pennsylvania) Indiana (PA), USA

#### DNA with honors

2015 - 2018

Bachelor's degree (National Diploma of Art) in Digital Art.

ENSAD (École Nationale Supérieure d'Art et de Design) Nancy, France

## **LANGUAGES**

French (native)

English (fluent)

Mandarin (intermediate)

German (basic)

## **TECHNICALS**

Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, Figma, XD, After Effects, InDesign, Audition, Logic Pro X

HTML, CSS, JS, Python, SQL (basic), PHP, C# (basic)

Maya, ZBrush, Blender, Substance Painter, Unity

TouchDesigner, Resolume Arena, MaxMSP

## **AWARDS**

Winner of Vibrations Urbaines Music Video Festival

For Philip Pentacle - Animal Chamber Apocalypse Beat (ACAB)

2022 :: Le Grillen, Ville de Colmar

1/2 English

## **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

### Montrez-moi vos muscles Record

Member and visual Artist at the music record Montrez-moi vos muscles (VJ, music video).

2019 - Present :: Strasbourg, France



#### WIUP radio station

Member of the Music Team, selecting musics and helping the Web Team.

2018 - 2019 :: Indiana (PA), USA

## **HUMMUß GAFFER**

Experiential art research with Clémence Fontaine.

2016 - 2018 :: Nancy, France

## **ENSAD BDE (student office)**

Communication manager, designing events' communication media (posters, socials media ads...)

2016 - 2017 :: Nancy, France

## **PRESS & CURATED WORK**

# PHILIP PENTACLE - ANIMAL CHAMBER APOCALYPSE BEAT [OCTOBER TONE]

2021:: Fedelab.fr

#### Un nouveau clip très animé pour Philip Pentacle

April 19th, 2021 :: Lalsace.fr

## [NOUVEAUTÉ] PHILIP PENTACLE - ANIMAL CHAMBER APOCALYPSE BEAT

March 3rd, 2021 :: Mesenceintesfontdefaut.com

## Les clips de la semaine #39

December 14th, 2020 :: Phenixwebtv.com

## PERFORMANCES & EXHIBITIONS (SELECTION)

Maison Mimir fête ses 10 ans, with Philip Pentacle and Epic Schmetterling.

March 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2020 :: MOLODOÏ, Strasbourg, France

## ART'ung Live, with Philip pentacle, Noyus and Epic Schmetterling.

February 15th, 2020 :: Local ART'ung, Willerhoff, France

#### CELEBRATION, with Epic Schmetterling.

December 5th, 2019 :: ENSAD, Nancy, France

## Limedia Party #1, as part of the RING festival, with CTL! soundsystem.

April 14th, 2018 :: Théatre de la Manufacture, Nancy, France

#### TECHNO, with ENSAD (BDE).

February 22<sup>nd</sup>, 2018 :: LNVRS club, Nancy, France

#### CTL PARTY!, with CTL! soundsystem.

November 4th, 2017 :: Ostra club, Nancy, France

#### Ph pas neutre: Jaquarius, with CTL! soundsystem.

October 6th, 2017:: LNVRS club, Nancy, France

## Festival Moumouth Fest, with Epic Schmetterling.

May 7th, 2017 :: Tanneries, Dijon, France

#### ARK4-Artem, with Latitudes 5.4.

Januray 19th, 2017:: CCAM, Vandoeuvre-les-Nancy, France

### Freshmen homecoming, with ENSAD (BDE).

December 8th, 2016:: Appart club, Nancy, France

## **RELATED SKILLS**

Illustration • Visual development • Web design • Concept art • Motion graphic • Photography • Video compositing • Video editing . Sound design

English 2/2